foreign
[Music]
if you think about cycling and the
history of Uganda cycling is one that
has always been with us
perhaps not so much in the southern part
of the country but more in the north so
historically you have people in the
north using Cycles to commute to
different places so even the vastness of
the northern part of Ghana and the under
development of the road infrastructure
and the lack of other transportation
cycling was the default of communicating
or committing from one place to the
other so that has been how cycling has
been positioned in our country so in the
northern part of Ghana it was more like
transport and also a way that youth
produce to entertain themselves and play
gradually is becoming a sport that is
seeing more professionalism coming into
it and that's where we come in as
potentially like insurance
but on the back of that also we had a
second Federation of Ghana also
beginning to start to have some
regulatory aspects of cycling as a sport
in this country there were several
attempts historically for them to be
part of the international cycling groups
for us to have more visibility as a
country participating in sports but this
was not the case it was a bit difficult
but gradually by the period we had some
groundbreaking results
I decided to learn how to cycle and
that's when I realized that second was a
very big thing in Ghana and that's when
I heard about the first Prudential
cycling event so Prudential has done so
well the first one in 2019
taking inspiration from our mother
company Prudential which sponsored the
first pro-ride in 2012 where they had
several circuits in London participating
as a sponsor but gradually it became
part of us in terms of the things we
like to do so Prudential Life as a
business always like to help make people
get the best out of life this means that
if we are making people get the best out
of life not only financially or through
insurance we help them through Wellness
so given that cycling has the advantage
of adding to your well-being and your
Wellness we are taking this very
seriously across the globe as the MC
mentioned here in Africa we have it in
two places Ghana being the first and
Zambia catching up very strongly and our
other markets also beginning to emulate
How We Do Prudential Life cycling events
in the country so provide is a big deal
for us in Ghana 2019 was the first one
having about 200 cyclists participating
covet had no cycling events for the
obvious lockdown reasons we came back in
2021 we had almost 200 people
participating 2022 we were all that you
saw the event which had professionals
which have amateurs great events and
recording zero accidents that's very
important for us in Prudential because
we believe in safe steps which is part
of the things that we do to keep safety
on the road so for us in Prudential
safety on the road is very very
important we like to enforce safety by
making sure you wear your crash helmets
you have your safety boots on and
recycle appropriately it looks like this
is a new space for Wii there's 13th is
the first time we are partnering with
Prudential and then Cowboy Navy I want
to say a big thank you to the team the
leadership for giving Sono take this
opportunity to partner for this year's
pro-life event
um generally as a medical doctor and I'm
sure we all know cause listening to
those who have spoken earlier on cycling
is good for all of us it's good for our
health it helps build our cardiovascular
system gives us a muscular endurance
so we are really excited to be
associated with this year's
um for Life event in September basically
sonotech would be offering free
um health screening basic health
screening package for both the cyclists
as well as all those who be around on
10th September to take part in the event
so thank you for this opportunity and
the whole team has solute looks forward
to being a part of this all important
event thank you
[Music]
thank you
foreign